Ramon Villafan Silva

Full Stack Developer | Portland, OR

ramonv.dev@gmail.com | LinkedIn | GitHub | Portfolio

SUMMARY

Dedicated developer with full-stack expertise. Recently contributed to a large codebase, creating a CMS for a Portland theater. Looking forward to collaborating on exciting projects with a development team and delivering quality products to clients.

SKILLS

Development: HTML | CSS | JavaScript | JSON | AJAX | TypeScript | C#

Frameworks/Libraries: ASP.NET MVC | EF | Next.js | React | jQuery | Bootstrap | Tailwind CSS

Database: SQL | MS SQL Server IDEs: Visual Studio | VS Code

Project Management: Agile, Scrum | Azure DevOps Server

Version Control: Git | GitHub

EXPERIENCE

Small-Business Website | Race Cleaning Services - Vancouver, WA

 Working with React.js and plain CSS to create a mobile-responsive UI <u>Live Project</u> | <u>Source Code</u>

Full Stack Developer | Prosper IT Consulting - Portland, OR

Dec. 2022 - Dec. 2022

Dec. 2022 - Jan. 2023

- Built a user-friendly management system by creating relevant user models, mapping such models to the database, and piecing together a frontend with a controller that provides support for asynchronous CRUD operations
- Managed an effective workflow by communicating with the development team daily to address issues and explore solutions

Read more about my collaborations on my Project Summary

Food Server | Jerusalem Cafe - Vancouver, WA

June 2022 - Oct. 2022

- Responsible for ensuring salad prep areas were clean and well-stocked before each shift
- Maintained full product knowledge of menu and specials
- Always mindful of sanitation and safety considerations when handling food
- Cleaned and reset tables promptly and efficiently for incoming customers, with a noticeable impact on reduced wait times

Delivery Assistant | RC Brothers - Portland Metro Area

June 2020 – June 2022

- Loaded and sorted items into box trucks to assist deliveries from popular home improvement retailers like
 Home Depot and Ashley
- Coordinated delivery schedules to ensure that services were consistently delivered in a timely and efficient manner

EDUCATION

Certification in C# and .NET Development | The Tech Academy - Portland, OR

Dec. 2022

Immersive technology boot camp with over 600 hours of instruction and hands-on programming.

• Studied core Computer Science principles, the internet, the World Wide Web, frontend web development, backend C# object-oriented programming, relational databases, version control, and project management

High School Diploma | Seton Catholic College Preparatory - Vancouver, WA

June 2022

College prep environment that empowers students to thrive, inspires moral development, and learning